

□ (+61) 410 206 745 | ■ me@michaelmcallister.org | # michaelmcallister.org | □ michaelmcallister | □ mpmcallister

Summary_

An enthusiastic Systems Engineer with 5+ years of experience designing, building (and troubleshooting!) some of the largest distributed systems in the world. A Linux enthusiast that loves automation and approaching operational problems with software solutions that scale.

As well as my technical skills, I've also delivered numerous presentations, training/mentoring and actively involved as a technical interviewer conducting over one hundred phone and in person interviews.

Skills__

Software Development Python, Bash, Java, Golang, CI/CD

Web JavaScript (ES6, TypeScript), React, HTML5, LESS, SASS

Systems & Networking Linux/*NIX, OSPF/BGP, TCP/IP, DNS, SQL/NoSQL

Cloud AWS Cloud Infrastructure: EC2, S3, RDS, VPC, Lambda

Work Experience _____

Amazon Web Services Sydney, Australia

SYSTEMS DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

Jul. 2016 - PRESENT

- · Scaling, monitoring and fire-fighting the Amazon RDS control plane powering the largest database fleet in the world
- · Designed and built a solution in Java to ingest and analyse alarming data to identify operational trends and patterns
- · Built supporting tools, including a web application in Python to understand and interpret ingested data both in real time and in automated weekly reports to stakeholders (to the GM level)
- Documented & drove process change that uses this data to influence the cadence and velocity of feature development
- Participate in hiring (100+ interviews) identifying potential in candidates to help fuel Amazon's expansive growth

Amazon Web Services Sydney, Australia

CLOUD SUPPORT ENGINEER Apr. 2015 - Jul. 2016

 Offered systems architecture advice and troubleshooting to customers using Amazon Web Services (EC2, Route 53, RDS, IAM, VPC, etc.) as solutions for their projects - focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance, scalability

Subject Matter Expert for EC2 Linux tasked with fleet-wide capacity management, and XEN dom0/hypervisor level troubleshooting

· Facilitated training sessions for new engineers on AWS EBS (Elastic Block Store), as well as advanced troubleshooting for tenured Engineers

iiNet Perth, Australia

SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR Aug. 2013 - Mar. 2015

- Part of a 24/7 on call rotation for the infrastructure and supporting services for Australia's #2 ISP (LDAP, DNS, E-Mail, Web Servers)
- Design, implementation and operational support for iiNet's DNS infrastructure (PowerDNS) that supported over 1 million active services across Australia
- · Maintain & document disaster recovery plans, policies and procedures

iiNet Perth, Australia

NETWORK ADMINISTRATOR

Aug. 2012 - Aug. 2013

- Proactive monitoring of the availability & performance of iiNet's key systems and applications, including F5 BIG-IP load balancers, *NIX Servers (Linux, Solaris), NetApp Storage Appliances and Juniper networking equipment
- · Physical installation, cabling and configuration of servers, and ADSL DSLAMs
- Incident Response & Post Mortem reviews

Education_

TAFE NSW

Charles Sturt University

Sydney, Australia

GRADUATE CERTIFICATE IN NETWORK AND SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATION

Jan. 2016 - Jan. 2017

ADVANCED DIPLOMA IN SYSTEMS DEVELOPMENT

Sydney, Australia Jan. 2015 - Jan. 2016

MICHAEL MCALLISTER · RÉSUMÉ FEBRUARY 25, 2018

Presentations

AWS CodeHack Sydney

PRESENTER FOR AMAZON SYDNEY HIRING EVENT & COMPETITION

Nov. 2017

- Organizer of a coding event designed to challenge attendees with 3 major prizes for top performers
- Presented an introduction to the role of System Devlopment Engineer, and the culture of AWS to 80+ attendees

BeerOps MegaMixer 2016

Sydney, Australia

Sydney, Australia

Dec. 2016

- REPRESENTATIVE FOR AMAZON WEB SERVICES
- Representing AWS at Sydneys largest DevOps meetup with 60+ attendees
- Presented Amazon Echo devices as prizes to winners of a competition ran at the event

AWS Summit Sydney

Sydney, Australia

Apr. 2016

BOOTH ATTENDANT & BUILDER FOR AMAZON SIMPLE BEER SERVICE

- A part of a small team that built an IoT Keggerator for the AWS Sydney Office that sends beer flow data to AWS
- · AWS technologies include: S3, API Gateway, Lambda, DynamoDB integrated with a Rasbperry Pi & Physical sensors
- Showcased at a booth at the AWS Summit Sydney 2016 to 3,000+ attendees
- See https://simplebeerservice.com

Referees

References available upon request.